<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | This is a blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://tkbremnes.github.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tkbremnes.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-02T02:11:27+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://tkbremnes.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Trond Kjetil]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some sort of intro]]></title>
    <link href="http://tkbremnes.github.com/blog/2012/01/02/some-sort-of-intro/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-02T01:21:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://tkbremnes.github.com/blog/2012/01/02/some-sort-of-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, this is me. I am a twenty-something student of informatics at the <a href="http://ntnu.edu">Norwegian University of Science and Technology</a>, where I'm currently studying for my Master's degree in Human-Computer Interaction. This page is meant to collect texts of varying degree of coherence about subject matters that interests me at any given moment to such an degree that I'll want to write something about it. I think the colloquial term is "blog". You can read it if you like. Hello world.</p>

<h3>What this blog is about</h3>

<p>Next fall, I'll be writing my Master's thesis about digital books in education, the details of which will be the subject of a later post. This blog is meant to collect my thoughts on the matter as the time draws ever nearer. I'm scheduled to be a part of a team writing a world changing game (alá Jane McGonigal's <a href="http://realityisbroken.org/">Reality is Broken</a>) this semester. I might write about that experience.</p>

<p>My interests include user experience (UX) design, web development, all thing neat and pretty, and all technology in general. Should be stuff here about that too.</p>

<h3>TK talks tech</h3>

<p>This blog is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a>, <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>, <a href="http://apple.com">OSX Snow Leopard</a>, <a href="http://macromates.com/">Textmate</a>, cheap coffee and expensive beer. The person at the keyboard might also be helping at times.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
